# SAMIR KHOURY

contact@bigbodysam.com

C

(914) 619-0335

9

Yonkers NY

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Ambitious web developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various CSS and HTML options, development platforms and security requirements.

# **SKILLS**

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks
- Responsive Web Design
- Bug Fixes
- Web and Application Servers
- · Back-End and Database Skills
- Customer Needs Assessments
- Mobile-Friendly Website
- Javascript
- HTML5
- CSS3
- NODEJS
- REACT
- RUBY
- RAILS
- GIT
- FIGMA
- POSTGRESQL
- RSPEC
- JEST
- SASS
- BOOTSTRAP
- REACTSTRAP

#### NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Critical Thinking
- Problem-Solving
- Active Listening
- Taking Cues and Direction
- Social Perceptiveness
- Live Music Performances
- · Musical Arrangements

# WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO, PROFILES

- · bigbodysam.com
- https://github.com/samirkhoury98
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/samir-khoury/

## **WORK HISTORY**

LEARN Academy - Teacher's Assistant San Diego, CA • 04/2022 - 05/2022

Darden Restaurants-Yard House, Outback Steakhouse - Server/Bartender/Saute Chef

Yonkers, NY • 04/2016 - 01/2022

- Cooled, stored, labeled and dated food products appropriately to maximize ingredient freshness when preparing recipes.
- Displayed correct recipes on monitor during prepping, frying and sautéing process to prepare ingredients and plate dishes to business standards.
- Complied with nutrition and sanitation regulations and safety standards by taking proper precautions to deliver high-quality food timely and simultaneously.
- Chopped vegetables, butchered meat and made sauces to prepare food for service.
- Cultivated warm relationships with regular customers.
- Worked with POS system to place orders, manage bills and handle complimentary items.
- Explained menu items and suggested appropriate options for food allergy concerns.
- Upsold high-profit items such as appetizers and mixed drinks to enhance sales numbers.
- Resolved guest and employee complaints to maintain complete customer satisfaction and workforce effectiveness.

- Music Composition
- Selecting Pieces
- Improvisation

#### **EDUCATION**

Westchester Community College Valhalla, NY

**Psychology** 

Mercy College Dobbs Ferry, NY

Psychology

Saunders Trades & Technical High School Yonkers, NY • 06/2016

High School Diploma

- Displayed enthusiasm and promoted excellent service to customers, successfully increasing referrals and walk-in business.
- Maintained thorough menu knowledge to sufficiently answer questions regarding menu item sourcing, ingredients and cooking methods.
- Arranged and prepared tables for customers to offer memorable experiences to guests and foster repeat business

# Walgreens - Retail Sales Associate

Yonkers, NY • 01/2014 - 02/2016

- Helped customers complete purchases, locate items and join reward programs.
- Checked pricing, scanned items, applied discounts and printed receipts to ring up customers.
- Organized store merchandise racks and displays to promote and maintain visually appealing environments.
- Volunteered for extra shifts during holidays and other busy periods to alleviate staffing shortages.
- Balanced and organized cash register by handling cash, counting change and storing coupons.
- Provided accurate information about promotions, customer programs and products, helping drive high customer retention.
- Stocked merchandise, clearly labeling items and arranging according to size or color.

# **LANGUAGES**

**Arabic** 

**Professional Working**